Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Crimes of War Project Archived Website, Aug 10, 2010-Aug 9, 2013; Crimes of War Project
  The Crimes of War Project (established in 1999 as a private, non-profit corporation) is a collaboration of journalists, lawyers and scholars dedicated to raising public awareness of the laws of war and their application to situations of conflict. Their goal is to promote understanding of international humanitarian law among journalists, policymakers, and the general public, in the belief that a wider knowledge of the legal framework governing armed conflict will lead to greater pressure to prevent breaches of the law, and to punish those who commit them. They seek to raise raise the level of understanding about the law among those reporting on war and war crimes; provide information for journalists, scholars, and the policy community about critical issues in modern armed conflict; encourage wider appreciation of international law as a framework for understanding and responding to conflicts around the world; promote consultation among journalists, legal experts and humanitarian agencies about how to increase compliance with international humanitarian law; and provide a forum for accessible debate about the current state of international law. The website contains a glossary, commentary arranged by region, and other articles. The website last updated in 2011.
  Prisoners of war |x Abuse of.; War (International law); War crimes -- United States.; War criminals -- United States.
- Cuban American Alliance Education Fund Archived Website, Feb 28, 2012- ongoing; Cuban American Alliance
  The Cuban American Alliance Education Fund, Inc. (CAAEF) is a nonprofit national network of Cuban Americans that educates the public on issues related to hardships resulting from United States-Cuba relations. The Alliance is a vehicle for the development of mutually beneficial engagements which promote understanding and human compassion. The website contains news and legislative updates, event listings, reader commentary, and gallery.
- Cypress Hills Local Development Corporation Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012 - ongoing; Cypress Hills Local Development Corporation
  The Cypress Hills Local Development Corporation (CHLDC), formed in May 1983, is a nonprofit community-based organization, serving approximately 8,000 residents per year through a comprehensive array of community service programs and neighborhood development projects in the Cypress Hills neighborhood in Brooklyn. Their mission is to revitalize the Cypress Hills community through housing preservation, economic development, and the positive development of youth and families. The website contains event and program listings.
  Housing.; Community organization.
- d.u.m.b.A collective Archived Website, Dec 11, 2009; Dumba Collective
  The Dumba Collective (1998-2006) was a non-profit arts collective in the Brooklyn NY, solely devoted to the contemporary art practices of the queer community. They offered space to local and international artists, primarily queer, and gave the majority of the profit back to the artist. The website was primarily a social networking one.
  Sexual politics.; Queer action/queer ideas.; Gay artists.; Art -- Political aspects.
- Deep Dish TV Archived Website, Jul 31, 2009- ongoing; Deep Dish TV Network
  Deep Dish TV was launched in 1986 by Paper Tiger TV as a distribution network, linking independent producers, programmers, community-based activists and viewers who support movements for social change and economic justice. The network has produced and distributed over 300 hours of television series that challenge the suppression of awareness, the corruption of language, and the perversion of logic that characterizes so much of corporate media. Deep Dish TV is committed to democratizing media by providing a national forum for programming created by community-based organizations and independent producers. Their programs are shown on over 200 public access cable stations around the country, on selected PBS stations, and received by thousands of satellite dish viewers nationwide on Free Speech TV channel 9415 on the DishNetwork and LinkTV on DirecTV.
  Public-access television -- United States
- Deep Dish TV Waves of Change Archived Website, Oct 14, 2011- ongoing; Deep Dish TV Network
  Waves of Change: The Many Voices of the Global Village is a multimedia project by Deep Dish Network designed to survey community media around the world by compiling and archiving the creative use of participatory communication globally. Waves of Change acts as a platform to share pieces that do not get seen outside of local coverage. The website includes an interactive map individual projects from their location on a world map and other media.
  Television broadcasting.; Alternative radio broadcasting.
- Demarcations Journal of Communist Theory and Polemic Archived Website, May 3, 2012- ongoing; Demarcations
  Demarcations: A Journal of Communist Theory and Polemic is a communist journal that contains revolutionary theory, Marxist thought, and applies communist theory on contemporary issues. The website contains articles. The last update was in 2009.
  Communism.
- Democracy Now! Archived Website, May 9, 2008- ongoing; Democracy Now! (Organization)
  Democracy Now!: Radio and TV News, is a daily progressive, independently syndicated TV/radio news program, hosted by Amy Goodman and Juan Gonzalez, airing on over 750 stations. Began on WBAI, in New York City in 1996, the program is funded entirely through contributions from listeners, viewers, and foundations and does not accept advertisers, corporate underwriting, or government funding. Democracy Now! is the flagship program for Pacifica Radio network.
  Alternative mass media |z United States.; Mass media criticism |z United States.; Gonzalez, Juan, 1947-; Goodman, Amy, 1957-
- Democratic Socialists of America Archived Website, Nov 26, 2008-ongoing; Democratic Socialists of America
  The Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was founded in 1983 as the result of the Merger of the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, founded in 1973 by Michael Harrington (1928-1989). He led the DSA until his death, and the New American Movement, a New Left organization founded in the early 1970s. DSA is affiliated with the Socialist International. The party's platform calls for reforms that weaken the influence of corporations in politics and give more power to working people. The website contains information on their campaigns and programs, which include student debt alleviation, immigrant rights, and the protection of social programs. The website also contains meeting minutes, chapter information, their publication, Democratic Left, their blog, Talking Union, their scholarship fund, and event listings.
  Socialism -- United States.; Harrington, Michael, 1928-1989
- Detainee Death Investigation Archived Website, Nov 24, 2009; United States. Department of Defense. Office of the Secretary of Defense and Joint Staff Reading Room
  Contains documents released in litigation concerning three detainee deaths at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp on June 10, 2006.
- Detainee Related Documents (U.S. Department of Defense) Archived Website, Jun 26, 2009-Jan 14, 2010; United States. Department of Defense. Office of the Secretary of Defense and Joint Staff Reading Room
  Contains documents obtained/posted via the Freedom of Information Act on the website of the Office of the Secretary of Defense and Joint Staff Reading Room.
- Detainees Positive Responses (pdf Object) Archived Website, Aug 23, 2009-ongoing; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
  The FBI on January 2, 2007 released documents related to an internal inquiry in 2004 of FBI personnel who had served at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba since September 11, 2001 and had observed any aggressive interview techniques, interrogations, or mistreatment of detainees by representatives of law enforcement, the military, or the FBI. There were no documented incidents involving FBI personnel. These documents include summaries of what FBI personnel observed.
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Crawl was limited to the host in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp & War Crimes (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2018 the original URL, http://foia.fbi.gov/guantanamo/detainees.pdf, was defunct and the new URL, https://vault.fbi.gov/Guantanamo%20/, was added to the collection. The accession number associated with this new URL is 2019.090.
- Dissent Magazine Archived Website, May 4, 2013- ongoing; Dissent (New York, N.Y.)
  Dissent Magazine, founded in 1954 by Irving Howe, is a quarterly leftist/social democratic intellectual magazine of politics and culture edited by Michael Kazin and Michael Walzer. Dissent's website contains direct links to articles from current issues and back issues, a blog, online articles, videos, and topical issues.
  Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.; Dissent
- Early American Marxism: A Repository of Source Material, 1864-1946 Archived Website, Sep 23, 2009- ongoing; Davenport, Tim, 1961-
  Early American Marxism is a repository of primary source Marxist materials dating from 1864-1946, collected by Tim Davenport. The website contains a historical background of significant groups established in the United States, including the First International, Language Federations, Socialist Labor Party, Socialist Party, Communist Party, Communist International, and other organizations. The primary resources are arranged by year, and summarized individually by Davenport.
  Marxism -- United States.; Trotskyism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.; Communism -- United States.
- Ecosocialist Coalition Archived Website, Apr 23, 2013- ongoing; Ecosocialist Contingent
  The Ecosocialist Contingent is a grouping of socialist organizations and supporters, dedicated to fighting global warming and its chief cause, capitalism. The websites contains their manifesto, conferences, and news.
  Environmentalism |x Political aspects |z United States.; Socialism -- United States.
- Ecosocialist Horizons Archived Website, Apr 18, 2013- ongoing; Ecosocialist Horizons
  Ecosocialist Horizons seeks to advance ecosocialism as a world-view and as a movement capable of offering real answers to the crises caused by capitalism. They work to providing news and analysis of ecosocialist concern through a multi-media website and other publications, to educate members to produce creative work and to organize events, actions, and convergences to advance diverse struggles towards an ecosocialist horizon. The ecosocialist movement aims to stop and to reverse the process of global warming in particular and of capitalist ecocide in general, and to construct a radical and practical alternative to the capitalist system. The website contains sections on the economic crisis, the food crisis, and global warming. It also contains event listings and articles.
  Socialism -- United States.; Environmentalism |x Political aspects |z United States.
- Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2008- ongoing; Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL)
  Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL) is a resource for the study of the international Trotskyist movement. It includes a "tree" of U.S. Trotskyist organizations, a list of pseudonyms, historical documents, and other materials.
  Trotskyism.; Socialism; Trotskyism -- United States.; Communism.
- Eugene V. Debs Foundation Archived Website, Aug 10, 2010- ongoing; Eugene V. Debs Foundation
  The Eugene V. Debs Foundation was founded in 1962 to preserve the Debs home and open it as a museum for the public, as well as act as a repository for Debs' papers and other artifacts. The Foundation also administers an award yearly to an individual that embodies "the spirit of progressivism, humanitarianism, and social criticism by Eugene V. Debs." The website also contains their biannual newsletter, a biography of Debs, information about the museum, and their essay contest.
  Socialists -- United States.; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926 |x Museums.; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926
- Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting Archived Website, Mar 8, 2010- ongoing; Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting (Organization)
  FAIR (Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting), a national media watch group, has been offering criticism of media bias and censorship since 1986. FAIR advocates greater diversity in the press, structural reform in the media, and works to expose neglected news stories. FAIR publishes Extra!, a magazine of media criticism, and produces the weekly radio program CounterSpin. In addition, they have a listserv through which they distribute regular action alerts to their international network of activists.
  Mass media criticism |z United States.; Alternative mass media |z United States.
- Federal Bureau of Investigation - Guantanamo Bay Investigation Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
  Contains a survey of 493 Federal Bureau of Investigation personnel asking whether they observed aggressive mistreatment, interrogations or interview techniques at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Torture |z United States.
- Ferguson Action Archived Website, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; Ferguson Action
  Website documenting the Black Lives Matter movement following the police murders of Mike Brown and Eric Garner in 2014. The website includes listings for actions, movement demands, and resources.
  Grand jury |z United States.; Black power.; Police brutality.
- Ferguson National Response Network, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing
  This site was originally created to list actions across the United States organized in response to the Ferguson, MO grand jury decision in the killing of unarmed African-American teenager Mike Brown in 2014. The website later expanded to list other events pertaining to police brutality, racial injustice, and the Black Lives Matter movement.
  Police brutality.; Grand jury |z United States.; Black power.
- Fight Imperialism Stand Together Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009-Jun 24, 2013; Fight Imperialism Stand Together
  Fight Imperialism Stand Together (FIST) is a national youth revolutionary group affiliated with the Workers World Party, a Marxist-Leninist communist organization of Trotskyist provenance. The organization advocates for the equality of race, sex, orientation, and the working class. The website contains news listings and their blog. The site last updated in 2011.
  Socialism and youth -- United States.; Communism -- United States.; Trotskyism -- United States.
- FOIA Post (2007): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- August 2007 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy
  Contains summaries of Federal court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by the Office or Information Policy during the month of August 2007.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Torture |z United States.; Military interrogation -- United States -- Evaluation.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Law and legislation -- United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- FOIA Post (2009): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- January 2009 Archived Website, Nov 20, 2009-Nov 30, 2010; United States. Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy
  Contains summaries of [Federal] court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by Office of Information Policy during the month of January 2009.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Law and legislation.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Torture |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- Freedom Road Socialist Organization Archived Website, March 2009-October 2019; Liberation Road
  Freedom Road Socialist Organization/Organicion Socialista del Camino Para la Libertad (FRSO/OSCL) was founded in 1985 when two small organizations, Proletarian Unity League (PUL) and the Revolutionary Workers Headquarters (RWH) merged. They are a network of revolutionary organizers that work to fight white supremacist capitalism. They work in the Black and Chicano movements and various immigrants' struggles, and in labor unions, workers centers and labor/community groups and coalitions. The website contains information on their platform and news and analysis. In April 2019, the organization changed its name to Liberation Road and changed its URL to https://roadtoliberation.org/.
  Socialist parties -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.
- Freedom Socialist Party Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007- ongoing; Freedom Socialist Party (U.S.)
  The Freedom Socialist Party (FSP) was founded in 1966 by former members of the Socialist Workers Party. The party is a revolutionary, socialist feminist organization, dedicated to the replacement of capitalist rule by a genuine workers' democracy that will guarantee full economic, social, political, and legal equality to women, people of color, gays, and all who are exploited, oppressed, and repelled by imperialism. The website contains their publication, Freedom Socialist, their platform, and information on their affiliates and chapters.
  Socialism -- United States.; Feminism -- United States.
- Global Exchange Archived Website, Apr 3, 2012- ongoing; Global Exchange (Organization)
  Global Exchange, founded in 1988, is an international human rights organization and resource center dedicated to promoting social, economic and environmental justice and educating the U.S. public about root causes of injustice and the impacts of U.S. government policies and corporate practices. The website contains information on their programs, reality travel tours, event listings, and news updates.
  Human rights.; Social justice.
- Grassroots Education Movement (NYC) Archived Website, Feb 26, 2010-Feb 25, 2013; Grassroots Education Movement to Defend Public Education
  The Grassroots Education Movement (GEM) educates and organizes educators, parents, students, and communities to defend public education. GEM works to stop privatization of schools, advocates equality and quality of public education services and rights for teachers and school workers. GEM also works to limit charter schools, supports teacher union rights, works to end the focus on high-stakes standardized testing and school closures, and raise awareness of racism and inequality in schools.
  Public schools -- New York (State) -- New York; Parents' and teachers' associations -- New York (State) -- New York; Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Student movements -- New York (N.Y.); United Federation of Teachers
- Grassroots Immigrant Justice Network Archived Website, Jul 5, 2011-Apr 5, 2011; Grassroots Immigrant Justice Network
  The Grassroots Immigrant Justice Network works to promote community dialogue on immigrant rights issues, labor issues, and immigration reform and is formed by leaders in the immigrant rights and labor movements across the country who believe that the immigration system must be based on human rights, not on increased enforcement measures, militarization of the border, and the criminalization of immigrant workers.
- Gray Panthers Archived Website, Nov 17, 2009- ongoing; Gray Panthers
  The Gray Panthers, founded in 1970 by Maggie Kuhn and friends, all of whom were retiring from national religious and social work organizations, to discuss the common problems faced by retirees — loss of income, loss of contact with associates and loss of one of our society's most distinguishing social roles, one's job. The organization has expanded, and also supports a single-payer system of health-care, as well as an increase in welfare payments, supporting peace activity, lifelong public education, the rights of workers, reproductive rights, abolition of the death penalty, legalization of same-sex marriage, the legalization of medical marijuana, and environmental activities through advocacy, education and action.
  Older women -- United States
- Green Anarchy Archived Website, Sep 21, 2007; Green Anarchy
  Green Anarchy, established in 2007, features news on anarchism and environmentalism.
- Green Party of New York State Archived Website, Sep 22, 2007-Nov 21, 2008; Greens/Green Party USA
  This is the website for the Green Party of New York State collective. It contained information on local caucuses, issues, and event listings.
  Green movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; Third parties (United States politics)
- Green Party of the United States Archived Website, Mar 26, 2009 - ongoing; Green Party of the United States
  The Green Party of the United States is a federation of state Green Parties. It was formed in 2001 as a successor to the older Association of State Green Parties (1996-2001). The Green Party is affiliated with the European Federation of Green Parties and the Federation of Green Parties of the Americas. The Green Party's goals include environmentalism, non-hierarchical participatory democracy, social justice, and respect for diversity, peace and nonviolence. The website contains news, election results, and organizational information.
  Third parties (United States politics); Green movement -- United States.; Greens/Green Party USA
- Greenwich House Archived Website, Aug 25, 2009 - ongoing; Greenwich House (New York, N.Y.)
  Greenwich House, founded in 1902 by Mary Kingsbury Simkhovitch, is a social settlement house in the Greenwich Village section of New York City. Initially founded to help New York's immigrant populations adjust to life in a new country. The organization by offers social and health services, cultural and educational programs, and opportunities for civic involvement to New Yorkers of all ages and backgrounds, including a chemical dependency program, classes in music and pottery, a nursery, and a senior center.
- Guerrilla Girls Archived Website, Sep 29, 2007 - ongoing; Guerrilla Girls (Group of artists)
  Guerrilla Girls are an anonymous group of feminists devoted to fighting against sexism within the visual fine art world. Started in New York City in 1985 to protest gender and racial inequality in the art world, members are known for the gorilla masks they wear to keep their anonymity, as well as for taking pseudonyms of dead women artists. The website lists their art projects, videos, lectures and appearances, exhibitions, and action projects.
  Art -- Political aspects.; Women artists -- Political activity -- United States.
- Guerrilla News Network, Feb 3, 2009-Aug 3, 2009
  Guerrilla News Network is an independent news organization with headquarters in New York City and production facilities in Berkeley, California. Our mission is to expose people to important global issues through cross-platform guerrilla programming.
  Anti-globalization movement |z United States.
- Haiti Grassroots Watch Archived Website, Oct 13, 2011-Jan 12, 2014; Haiti Grassroots Watch